Inventory of the Miller Upton papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) File
  - Subject file
    - Americans for the Universality of UNESCO, Jack E. Fobes, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 19: 4)
    - Committee for Decade for Action to Combat Racism, Whitney M. Young, 1970-1975 (Box-folder 19: 5)
    - Congressional Committee, 1976 (Box-folder 19: 6)
      Includes Upton's testimony
    - International education, 1964-1971 (Box-folder 19: 7-9)
    - Preparation for testimony before Committee on International Organizations, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 19: 10)
      Includes Upton's speech and report for UNESCO General Conference, Eighteenth Session
    - Preparation for testimony before Committee on International Organizations (cont'd.), 1972-1976 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Reports
    - General, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 20: 2)
    - Third Regional Conference of Ministers of Education and Ministers Responsible for Economic Planning of Member States in Asia, 1971 (Box-folder 20: 3)
  - Speech, "UNESCO--To Be or Not To Be,", 1960-1985 (Box-folder 20: 4)
  - Speeches and writings by others
    - "The First Thirty Years," Radio UNESCO, 1976 (Box-folder 20: 5)
    - Adiseshiah, Malcolm S., "Adult Education in the Seventies,", 1970 (Box-folder 20: 6)
    - Partan, Daniel G., "Documentary Study of the Politicization of UNESCO,", 1975-1976 (Box-folder 20: 7-8)
  - Travel vouchers, 1976 (Box-folder 20: 9)
  - United States National Commission file
    - General, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 20: 10)
    - General (cont'd.), 1974-1976 (Box-folder 21: 1-2)
    - Cultural consultation, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 21: 3)
    - Meetings
      - Annual meeting
        - Thirty-sixth meeting, 1972 (Box-folder 21: 4)
        - Thirty-seventh meeting, 1973 (Box-folder 21: 5)
        - Thirty-ninth meeting, 1975 (Box-folder 21: 6)
      - Executive Committee
        - Eighty-first meeting, 1975 (Box-folder 21: 7)
        - Eighty-second meeting, 1976 (Box-folder 21: 8)
      - Sixth Regonial Conference of European National Commissions, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 21: 9)
    - Russia trip, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 21: 10-11)
    - Russia trip (cont'd.), 1973-1974 (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - Task force on quality of representation, 1975 (Box-folder 22: 2)
    - Working paper on agenda items for UN conference on human environment, 1970 (Box-folder 22: 3)
- Association of American Colleges File
  - Report and notes on future role of the association, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 22: 4)
  - Board of Directors meeting, 1976 (Box-folder 22: 5)
  - Committees on Constituency and Structure and Program Development, 1976 (Box-folder 22: 7-9)
  - Meeting materials, reports, and printed matter, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 22: 10)
  - Carlson Report, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 22: 11)
  - Commission on Liberal Learning, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 22: 12)
  - National Association of Independent Colleges and Universities (NAICU), 1976 (Box-folder 22: 13)
- Continuing Revenue Survey Commission File
  - Correspondence, meeting minutes, and printed matter, 1960 (Box-folder 23: 1)
  - Report, 1960 (Box-folder 23: 2)
  - Meeting minutes, memoranda, charts, and notes, 1960 (Box-folder 23: 3)
  - Correspondence and report drafts, 1960 (Box-folder 23: 4-5)
  - Report, "Industrial Growth, Tax Burden, and the Federal System,", undated (Box-folder 23: 6)
  - Correspondence
    - Doyle, James, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 23: 7)
    - Larkin, Edwin, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 23: 8)
    - Loeb, John, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 23: 9)
  - Tax sources and incidence, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 23: 10)
  - Tax sharing, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 23: 11)
  - Tax burden, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 23: 12)
  - Tax committee, general, 1960 (Box-folder 23: 13)
  - Correspondence, reports, and printed matter, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 23: 14-17)
  - Report, 1960 (Box-folder 24: 1)
- Speeches and Writings
  - Business Finance Handbook, 1953 (Box-folder 24: 2)
  - "An Economic Appraisal of Convenience and Advantage Licensing by Small-Loan Statutes," in The Journal of Business of the University of Chicago, 1952 (Box-folder 24: 3)
  - "The Economics of Fair Changes for Consumer Loans,", 1951 (Box-folder 24: 4)
  - "The Great Society: A Second Opinion,", undated (Box-folder 24: 5)
- Bill Wenzler Project, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 24: 6)
- Case for private college, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 24: 7)
- Case statements, 1976 (Box-folder 24: 8)
  Includes "Report to the Members of the Council for Higher Education of the United Church of Christ."
- Miscellany, correspondence and printed matter, 1975-1987 (Box-folder 24: 9)
- Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars File, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 24: 10)
- Federal Union File
  - Correspondence and printed matter, 1969-1976 (Box-folder 24: 11-12)
- Printed matter related to higher education and churches, 1947-1976, undated (Box-folder 25: 1-2)